<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<?rfc toc="yes"?>
<?rfc tocompact="yes"?>
<?rfc tocdepth="3"?>
<?rfc tocindent="yes"?>
<?rfc symrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc sortrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc comments="yes"?>
<?rfc inline="yes"?>
<?rfc compact="yes"?>
<?rfc subcompact="no"?>
<rfc
    category="std"
    docName="draft-ietf-bfd-optimizing-authentication-latest"
    ipr="trust200902"
    updates="5880"
    submissionType="IETF"
    consensus="true">
  <front>
    <title abbrev="BFD Authentication Optimization">Optimizing BFD
    Authentication</title>

    <author fullname="Mahesh Jethanandani" initials="M."
            surname="Jethanandani">
      <organization>Kloud Services</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street/>
          <city/>
          <region/>
          <code/>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
        <phone/>
        <facsimile/>
        <email>mjethanandani@gmail.com</email>
        <uri/>
      </address>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Ashesh Mishra" initials="A" surname="Mishra">
      <organization>Aalyria Technologies</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street/>
          <city/>
          <region/>
          <code/>
          <country/>
        </postal>
        <phone/>
        <email>ashesh@aalyria.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Ankur Saxena" initials="A" surname="Saxena">
      <organization>Ciena Corporation</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>3939 N 1st Street</street>
          <city>San Jose</city>
          <region>CA</region>
          <code>95134</code>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
        <phone/>
        <facsimile/>
        <email>ankurpsaxena@gmail.com</email>
        <uri/>
      </address>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Manav Bhatia " initials="M." surname="Bhatia ">
      <organization>Google</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>Doddanekkundi</street>
          <city>Bangalore</city>
          <code>560048</code>
          <country>India</country>
	</postal>
        <email>mnvbhatia@google.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jeffrey Haas" initials="J." surname="Haas">
      <organization>Juniper Networks</organization>
      <address>
        <email>jhaas@pfrc.org</email>
      </address>
    </author>

    <date/>
    <keyword>BFD</keyword>
    <keyword>authentication</keyword>

    <abstract>
      <t>This document describes an optimization to BFD Authentication as
      described in Section 6.7 of BFD RFC 5880. This document updates RFC
      5880.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>

  <middle>
    <section anchor="introduction" title="Introduction">
      <t>Authenticating every <xref target="RFC5880">BFD</xref> control packet
      with <xref target="RFC1321">MD5
      Message-Digest Algorithm </xref>, or Secure Hash Algorithm (SHA-1)
      is a computationally intensive process. This makes it
      difficult, if not impossible to authenticate every packet - particularly
      at faster rates. Also, the recent escalating series of attacks on MD5
      and SHA-1 described in <xref target="SHA-1-attack1">Finding Collisions
      in the Full SHA-1 </xref> and <xref target="SHA-1-attack2">New Collision
      Search for SHA-1 </xref> raise concerns about their remaining useful
      lifetime as outlined in <xref target="RFC6151">Updated Security
      Considerations for the MD5 Message-Digest and the HMAC-MD5 Algorithm
      </xref> and <xref target="RFC6194">Security Considerations for the SHA-0
      and SHA-1 Message-Digest Algorithm </xref>. If replaced by stronger
      algorithms, the computational overhead, will make the task of
      authenticating every packet even more difficult to achieve.</t>

      <t>
	This document proposes that BFD control packets that signal a
	state change, a demand mode change (to D bit), a poll sequence
	change (P or F bit change) be categorized as a significant
	change. Control packets that do not require a poll sequence,
	such as a change in bfd.RequiredMinRxInterval or
	bfd.RequiredMinTxInterval, are also considered as a
	significant change. In other words, the contents of an Up
	packet MUST NOT change aside from the authentication section
	without stronger authentication to take advantage of the
	method described in this document.
      </t>

      <t>In the Up state, most packets that are transmitted and received have no state change
      associated with them. Limiting authentication to packets that affect a
      BFD session's state allows more sessions to be supported with this
      optimized method of authentication.</t>

      <t>
	Once the session has reached the Up state, the session can
	choose a less computationally intensive Auth Type.  Currently, this
	includes:

	<ul>
	  <li>
	    Meticulous Keyed ISAAC authentication as described in
	    <xref target="I-D.ietf-bfd-secure-sequence-numbers"/>.
	    This authentication type prevents the attack when the Up packets do
	    not change, because only the paired devices know the shared secret,
	    key, and sequence number to select the ISAAC result.
	  </li>
	</ul>
      </t>

      <t>
        When using optimized methods of authentication, BFD sessions should
	periodically test the session using strong authentication.  Strong
	authentication is tested using a Poll sequence. To test strong
	authentication, a Poll sequence SHOULD be initiated by the sender using
	the strong authentication Auth Type rather than the chosen optimized
	Auth Type. If a control packet with the Final (F) bit is not received
	within the Detect Interval, the session has been compromised, and should
	be brought down. The interval for initiating a Poll sequence can be
	configured depending on the capability of the system.
      </t>

      <t>
	Most packets transmitted on a BFD session are BFD Up packets.
	Strongly authenticating a small subset of these packets with a Poll
	sequence as described above, for example every one minute,
	<!-- XXX JMH - one minute is probably now too small -->
	significantly reduces the computational demand for the system
	while maintaining security of the session across the
	configured strong reauthentication interval.
      </t>

      <section title="Requirements Language">
        <t>The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL NOT",
        "SHOULD", "SHOULD NOT", "RECOMMENDED", "MAY", and "OPTIONAL" in this
        document are to be interpreted as described in <xref
        target="RFC2119">BCP 14</xref> <xref target="RFC8174"/> when, and only
        when, they appear in all capitals, as shown here.</t>
      </section>

      <section anchor="note-to-rfc-editor" title="Note to RFC Editor">
        <t>
	  This document uses several placeholder values throughout the
	  document. Please replace them as follows and remove this
	  note before publication.
	</t>

        <t>
	  RFC XXXX, where XXXX is the number assigned to this document
	  at the time of publication.
	</t>

        <t>
	  YYYY-MM-DD with the actual date of the publication of this
	  document.
	</t>
      </section>

      <section title="Terminology">
        <t>The following terms used in this document have been defined in
        <xref target="RFC5880">BFD</xref>.</t>

        <t><list style="symbols">
	    <t>Auth Type</t>
            <t>Detect Multiplier</t>
            <t>Detection Time</t>
          </list></t>

        <t>The following terms are introduced in this document.</t>

        <texttable style="full">
          <ttcol>Term</ttcol>
          <ttcol>Meaning</ttcol>
          <c>significant change</c>
          <c>
	    State change, a demand mode change (to D bit) or a poll
	    sequence change (P or F bit). Control packets that do not
	    require a poll sequence, such as bfd.RequiredMinRxInterval
	    bfd.RequiredMinTxInterval, or bfd.DetectMult are also
	    considered as a significant change.
	  </c>
          <c>configured strong reauthentication interval</c>
          <c>
	    Interval at which BFD control packets are retried with a
	    stronger authentication.
	  </c>
        </texttable>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section title="Authentication Mode  ">
      <t>The cryptographic authentication mechanisms specified in <xref
      target="RFC5880">BFD</xref> describes enabling and disabling of
      authentication as a one time operation. As a security precaution, it
      mentions that authentication state be allowed to change at most once.
      Once enabled, every packet must have Authentication Bit set and the
      associated Authentication Type appended. In addition, it states that an
      implementation SHOULD NOT allow the authentication state to be changed
      based on the receipt of a BFD control packet.</t>

      <t>This document proposes that an authentication mode that permits both a
      strong authentication mode and a less expensive "optimized" mode to be
      used within the same BFD session.  This pairing of a strong and an
      optimized mode of authentication is carried in new BFD authentication
      types representing a given authentication type pairing.</t>

      <t>
	The proposal outlines which BFD control packets are required
	to be strongly authenticated. A BFD control packet that fails
	authentication is discarded, or a BFD control packet that was
	supposed to be strongly authenticated, but was not; e.g. a significant
	change packet, is discarded. However, there is no change to
	the state machine for BFD, as the decision of a significant
	change is still decided by how many valid consecutive packets
	were received.
      </t>

      <t>
	In this proposal, the contents of an Up packet MUST NOT change
	aside from the authentication section without stronger
	authentication.  The full procedure is documented in the following
	sections.
      </t>
    </section>

    <section title="Signaling Optimized Authentication">
      <t>
        When the Authentication Present (A) bit is set and the Auth Type is a
	type supporting Optimized BFD Authentication
	(<xref target="auth-type"/>), the Auth Type signals a
	pairing of a strong authentication type and an optimized authentication
	type.  This pairing is advertised in a single Auth Type value in order
	to permit implementations to be aware that:

	<ul>
	  <li>Optimized BFD procedures will be in use.</li>
	  <li>The pairing of the strong and optimized authentication mechanisms
	      will be used for that session.</li>
	  <li>The current strong or optimized mode will be carried as described
	      below:</li>
	</ul>
      </t>

      <t>
	<figure
	    align="center" title="Common BFD Authentication Section">
	  <artwork><![CDATA[
       0                   1                   2                   3
       0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0 1
      +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
      |   Auth Type   |   Auth Len    |  Auth Key ID  |  Optimized    |
      +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
      |                   Authentication Specific Data                ~
      +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
	]]></artwork>
	</figure>
      </t>

      <t>
        The Meticulous Keyed MD5, Meticulous Keyed SHA-1, and Meticulous Keyed
	ISAAC authentication sections define the fourth octet as "Reserved".
	This document repurposes the "Reserved" field as the "Optimized" field
	when used for authentication types for optimized BFD procedures.
      </t>

      <t>
        The values of the Optimized field are:
	<ol>
	  <li>
	    When using the strong authentication type for optimized
	    BFD Auth Types.
	  </li>
	  <li>
	    When using the optimized authentication type for optimized
	    BFD Auth Types.
	  </li>
        </ol>
      </t>

      <t>
        Authentication Specific Data: When using the strong authentication type,
	the remainder of the authentication section carries that type's data.
      </t>

      <t>
        For example, for Auth Type "Optimized MD5 Meticulous Keyed ISAAC
	Authentication" (type TBD):
      </t>
      <t>
	When Optimized is 1, the format of the authentication section is the
	same as <xref target="RFC5880" section="4.3"/>, excepting that Auth Type
	is still TBD and that Reserved is set to 1.
      </t>
      <t>
	When Optimized is 2, the format of the authentication section is the
	same as <xref target="I-D.ietf-bfd-secure-sequence-numbers" section="5"/>,
	excepting that Auth Type is still TBD and that Reserved is set to 2.
      </t>

      <section title="Error Handling">
        <t>
	  If the received BFD Control packet contains an optimized
	  authentication type using these procedures and the Optimized field is
	  not 1 or 2, then the received packet MUST be discarded.
	</t>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section title="Optimized Authentication Operations">
      <t>
        As noted in Section 2, when using optimized BFD procedures, strong
	authentication is used in the BFD state machine to bring a BFD session
	to the Up state or to make any change of the BFD parameters as carried
	in the BFD Control packet when in the Up state.
      </t>

      <t>
        Once the BFD session has reached the Up state, the BFD Up state MUST
	be signaled to the remote BFD system using the strong authentication for
	at least Detect Mult packets before switching to the optimized
	authentication mode.  This is to permit mechanisms such as 
	<xref target="I-D.ietf-bfd-secure-sequence-numbers">
	Meticulous Keyed ISAAC for BFD Authentication</xref> to be
	bootstrapped before switching to optimized authentication.
      </t>

      <t>
        It is RECOMMENDED that when using optimized authentication that
	implementations switch from strong authentication to optimized
	authentication after sending at least Detect Mult packets.  In the
	circumstances where a BFD session successfully reaches the Up state with
	strong authentication, but there are problems with the optimized
	authentication, this will permit the remote system to tear down the
	session as quickly as possible.
      </t>

      <t>
        BFD sessions using optimized authentication that succeed in reaching the
	Up state using strong authentication and fail using the optimized
	authentication SHOULD bring the issue to the attention of the operator.
	Further, implementations MAY wish to throttle session restarts.
      </t>

      <t>
	It is further RECOMMENDED that BFD implementations using optimized
	authentication defer notifying their client that the session has reached
	the Up state until it has transitioned to using the optimized
	authentication mode.  In the event where optimized authentication is
	failing in the protocol, this avoids propagating the failed transitions
	to optimized mode to the clients.
      </t>
    </section>

    <section anchor="opt-auth-yang-model" title="Optimizing Authentication YANG Model">
      <section anchor="data-model-overview" title="Data Model Overview">
	<t>
	  The <xref target="RFC7950">YANG 1.1</xref> model defined in
	  this document augments the "ietf-bfd" module to add
	  configuration relevant to the management of the feature
	  defined in this document. In particular, it adds crypto
	  algorithms that are described in this model, and in 
	  <xref target="I-D.ietf-bfd-secure-sequence-numbers">
	  Meticulous Keyed ISAAC for BFD Authentication</xref>.
	  It adds a feature statement to
	  enable optimized authentication. Finally, it adds a flag to
	  enable optimized authentication, an interval value that
	  specifies how often the BFD session should be
	  re-authenticated once it is in the Up state, and the key chain
	  that should be used in the Up state.
	</t>
      </section>
      <section anchor="tree-diagram" title="Tree Diagram">
	<t>
	  The tree diagram for the YANG modules defined in this
	  document use annotations defined in <xref
	  target="RFC8340">YANG Tree Diagrams.</xref>.
	</t>
	<t>
	  <figure>
            <artwork><![CDATA[
	    INSERT_TEXT_FROM_FILE(../bin/ietf-bfd-opt-auth@YYYY-MM-DD-tree.txt,69)
	    ]]></artwork>
          </figure>
	</t>
      </section>
      <section anchor="the-yang-model" title="The YANG Model">
	<t>
	  This YANG module imports <xref target="RFC8177">YANG Key
	  Chain </xref>, <xref target="RFC8349">A YANG Data Model for
	  Routing Management (NMDA version)</xref>, and <xref
	  target="RFC9314">YANG Data Model for Bidirectional Forwarding
	  Detection (BFD)</xref>.
	</t>
	<t>
	  Implementations supporting the optimization procedures defined in
	  this document enable optimization by using one of the newly 
	  defined key-chain crypto-algorithms defined in this YANG module.
	</t>
	<t>
	  <figure>
            <artwork><![CDATA[
	    <CODE BEGINS> file "ietf-bfd-opt-auth@YYYY-MM-DD.yang"
	    INSERT_TEXT_FROM_FILE(../bin/ietf-bfd-opt-auth@YYYY-MM-DD.yang,69)
	    <CODE ENDS>
	    ]]></artwork>
          </figure>
	</t>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section anchor="IANA" title="IANA Considerations">
      <t>
	This documents requests two new authentication types, one URI,
	one YANG model, and an update to an existing IANA YANG model.
      </t>
      <section anchor="auth-type" title="Auth Type">
	<t>
	  This document requests an update to the registry titled "BFD
	  Authentication Types". IANA is requested to assign two new
	  BFD AuthType:
	  <ul>
	    <li>
	      <xref target="I-D.ietf-bfd-secure-sequence-numbers"
	      sectionFormat="parens"
	      section="meticulous-keyed-isaac-authentication">
	      Optimized MD5 Meticulous Keyed ISAAC Authentication</xref>,
	      with a suggested value of 7.
	    </li>
	    <li>
	      <xref target="I-D.ietf-bfd-secure-sequence-numbers"
	      sectionFormat="parens"
	      section="meticulous-keyed-isaac-authentication">
	      Optimized SHA-1 Meticulous Keyed ISAAC Authentication</xref>,
	      with a suggested value of 8.
	    </li>
	  </ul>
	</t>
      </section>
      <section anchor="ietf-xml-registry" title="IETF XML Registry">
	<t>
	  This document registers one URIs in the "ns" subregistry of
	  the "IETF XML" registry <xref target="RFC3688"/>. Following
	  the format in <xref target="RFC3688"/>, the following
	  registration is requested:
	</t>
        <t>
	  <figure>
            <artwork>
	      <![CDATA[
URI: urn:ietf:params:xml:ns:yang:ietf-bfd-opt-auth
Registrant Contact: The IESG
XML: N/A, the requested URI is an XML namespace.
	      ]]>
	    </artwork>
          </figure>
	</t>
      </section>
      <section anchor="yang-module-names" title="The YANG Module Names Registry">
        <t>
	  This document registers one YANG modules in the "YANG Module
	  Names" registry <xref target="RFC6020"/>. Following the
	  format in <xref target="RFC6020"/>, the following
	  registrations are requested:
	</t>
        <t>
	  <figure>
	    <artwork>
	      <![CDATA[
name:         ietf-bfd-opt-auth
namespace:    urn:ietf:params:xml:ns:yang:ietf-bfd-opt-auth
prefix:       bfdoa
reference:    RFC XXXX
	      ]]>
	    </artwork>
          </figure>
	</t>
      </section>
      <section anchor="updated-iana-module" title="Updated IANA Module">
	<t>
	  This document also requests an update to an existing IANA
	  YANG module described in <xref
	  target="updated-bfd-iana-module">Updated BFD IANA
	  Module</xref>
	</t>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section anchor="Security" title="Security Considerations">
      <t>
	The YANG module specified in this document defines a schema
	for data that is designed to be accessed via network
	management protocols such as <xref
	target="RFC6241">NETCONF</xref> or <xref
	target="RFC8040">RESTCONF</xref>. The lowest NETCONF layer is
	the secure transport layer, and the mandatory-to-implement
	secure transport is <xref target="RFC6242">Secure Shell
	(SSH)</xref>. The lowest RESTCONF layer is HTTPS, and the
	mandatory-to-implement secure transport is <xref
	target="RFC8446">TLS</xref>. The <xref
	target="RFC8341">NETCONF Access Control Model (NACM) </xref>
	provides the means to restrict access for particular NETCONF
	or RESTCONF users to a preconfigured subset of all available
	NETCONF or RESTCONF protocol operations and content.
      </t>

      <t>
	There are a number of data nodes defined in this YANG module
	that are writable/creatable/deletable (i.e., config true,
	which is the default).  These data nodes may be considered
	sensitive or vulnerable in some network environments. Write
	operations (e.g., edit-config) to these data nodes without
	proper protection can have a negative effect on network
	operations. Some of the subtrees and data nodes and their
	sensitivity/vulnerability are described here.
      </t>

      <ul>
	<li>
	  'reauth-interval' specifies the interval in Up state, after
	  which a strong authentication SHOULD be performed to prevent
	  a Person-In-The-Middle (PITM) attack. If this interval is
	  set very low, the utility of these optimization procedures is
	  lessened. If this interval is set very high, attacks detected
	  by the strong authentication mechanisms may happen overly
	  late.
	</li>
      </ul>

      <t>
	Some of the readable data nodes in this YANG module may be
	considered sensitive or vulnerable in some network
	environments. It is thus important to control read access
	(e.g., via get, get-config, or notification) to these data
	nodes.
      </t>

      <t>
	There are no read-only data nodes defined in this model.
      </t>

      <t>
	Some of the RPC operations in this YANG module may be
	considered sensitive or vulnerable in some network
	environments. It is thus important to control access to these
	operations.
      </t>

      <t>
	There are no RPC operations defined in this model.
      </t>

      <t>
	The approach described in this document enhances the ability
	to authenticate a BFD session by taking away the onerous
	requirement that every BFD control packet be authenticated. By
	authenticating packets that affect the state of the session,
	the security of the BFD session is maintained. In this mode,
	packets that are a significant change but are not
	authenticated, are dropped by the system. Therefore, a
	malicious user that tries to inject a non-authenticated
	packet; e.g. with a Down state to take a session down will
	fail. That combined with the proposal of using sequence number
	defined in <xref
	target="I-D.ietf-bfd-secure-sequence-numbers">Meticulous Keyed
	ISAAC for BFD Authentication</xref> further enhances the
	security of BFD sessions.
      </t>
    </section>

    <section title="Contributors" anchor="contributors">
      <t>
	The authors of this document would like to acknowledge Reshad
	Rahman as a contributor to this document.
      </t>
    </section>
  </middle>

  <back>
    <references title="Normative References">
      <?rfc include="reference.RFC.2119.xml"?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.3688.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.5880.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.6020.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.6241.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.6242.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.7950.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.8040.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.8174.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.8177.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.8340.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.8341.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.8349.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.8446.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.9127.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.9314.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.I-D.ietf-bfd-secure-sequence-numbers.xml'?>
    </references>

    <references title="Informative References">
      <reference anchor="SHA-1-attack1">
        <front>
          <title>Finding Collisions in the Full SHA-1</title>

          <author initials="X." surname="Wang">
            <organization/>
          </author>

          <author initials="Y." surname="Yin">
            <organization/>

            <address>
              <postal>
                <street/>

                <city/>

                <region/>

                <code/>

                <country/>
              </postal>

              <phone/>

              <facsimile/>

              <email/>

              <uri/>
            </address>
          </author>

          <author initials="H." surname="Yu">
            <organization/>

            <address>
              <postal>
                <street/>

                <city/>

                <region/>

                <code/>

                <country/>
              </postal>

              <phone/>

              <facsimile/>

              <email/>

              <uri/>
            </address>
          </author>

          <date year="2005"/>
        </front>
      </reference>

      <reference anchor="SHA-1-attack2">
        <front>
          <title>New Collision Search for SHA-1</title>

          <author initials="X." surname="Wang">
            <organization/>
          </author>

          <author initials="A." surname="Yao">
            <organization/>

            <address>
              <postal>
                <street/>

                <city/>

                <region/>

                <code/>

                <country/>
              </postal>

              <phone/>

              <facsimile/>

              <email/>

              <uri/>
            </address>
          </author>

          <author initials="F." surname="Yao">
            <organization/>

            <address>
              <postal>
                <street/>

                <city/>

                <region/>

                <code/>

                <country/>
              </postal>

              <phone/>

              <facsimile/>

              <email/>

              <uri/>
            </address>
          </author>

          <date year="2005"/>
        </front>
      </reference>

      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.1321.xml'?>

      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.6151.xml'?>

      <?rfc include='reference.RFC.6194.xml'?>
      <?rfc include='reference.I-D.ietf-bfd-stability.xml'?>
    </references>
    <section anchor="updated-bfd-iana-module" title="Updated BFD IANA Module">
      <t>
	This section carries the updated IANA BFD Module,
	iana-bfd-types.yang module, first defined in <xref
	target="RFC9127">YANG Data Model for Bidirectional Forward
	Detection (BFD)</xref>. The updated module carries three new
	authentication type enum definitions, 'null' with a suggested
	value of 6, and 'optimized-md5-meticulous-keyed-isaac' with a
	suggested value of 7, and
	'optimized-sha1-meticulous-keyed-isaac' with a suggested value
	of 8. Note, the null enum type is used by <xref
	target="I-D.ietf-bfd-stability">BFD Stability</xref> only, but
	is being defined here to make sure changes to this YANG module
	do not cause a conflict. This module should replace the
	version that currently exists in the IANA registry.
      </t>
	<t>
          <figure>
            <artwork><![CDATA[
	    <CODE BEGINS> file "iana-bfd-types@YYYY-MM-DD.yang"
            INSERT_TEXT_FROM_FILE(../bin/iana-bfd-types@YYYY-MM-DD.yang,68)
	    <CODE ENDS>
            ]]>
            </artwork>
          </figure>
	</t>
    </section>
    <section anchor="examples" title="Examples">
      <t>
	This section tries to show some examples in how the model can
	be configured.
      </t>
      <section anchor="example-a.1.1" title="Single Hop BFD Configuration">
	<t>
          This example demonstrates how a Single Hop BFD session can
          be configured for optimized authentication.
	</t>
	<t>
          <figure>
            <artwork><![CDATA[
            INSERT_TEXT_FROM_FILE(../src/yang/example-ip-sh-bfd-config-a.1.1.xml,68)
            ]]>
            </artwork>
          </figure>
	</t>
      </section>
    </section>      
  </back>
</rfc>
